Clement F. Haynsworth Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- United States Court of Appeals File, 1955-1989 (Box 6-201)
  - Case File, 1956-1989 (Box 7-159)
    - Other circuit cases
      - Third circuit, 1984
        - Bolden v. Thornburgh, No. 83-1544
        - Flynn v. Bass Bros. Enters., No. 83-1725
        - United States v. Osticco, No. 83-3635
        - Soroka v. Nationwide Mut. Ins. Co., No. 83-5757
        - Storage Technology v. Blitt, No. 83-5794
        - United States v. Parton, No. 84-1048
        - Miscellany
      - Seventh circuit
        - 1984
          - Byrd v. Secretary, Health and Human Servs., No. 83-3212
          - Vallone v. Local Union No. 705, Int'l Bhd. of Teamsters, No. 84-1014
          - In re Tarnow, No. 84-1221
          - United States v. Yocum, No. 84-1502
          - Dillon v. Duckworth, No. 84-2208
        - 1985
          - Walker v. Maccabees, No. 83-2535
          - Mort Edidin, Inc. v. Aetna Ins. Co., No. 83-2628
          - Martz v. Union Labor Life Ins. Co., No. 83-2632
          - Cole v. Bertsch Vending Co., No. 83-2742
          - Donovan v. Allied Indus. Workers of Am., No. 83-2831 (Box 154)
          - United States v. United States Currency, $2,857, No. 83-3107
          - Duir v. John Alden Life Ins. Co., No. 83-3138
          - Novus Property Co. v. Bankers Trust Co., No. 83-3162
          - United States ex. rel. Dowd v. Lane, No. 83-3304
          - General Motors Acceptance Corp. v. American Oil Co., No. 84-1025
          - Thoman v. Bultema Dock & Dredge Co., No. 84-1291
          - Ehlenfeldt v. C. W. Transp., No. 84-1302
          - United States ex. rel. Broughton-El v. Thieret, No. 84-1388
        - Miscellany, 1983-1984
      - Ninth circuit
        - 1982
          - Crom Corp. v. Crom, No. 80-4434
          - In re Oceanside Properties, No. 80-4532
          - United States v. Almaneih, No. 81-1297
          - Boggs v. Bancroft-Whitney Co., No. 81-4129
          - Equal Employment Opportunity Comm'n v. Plumbers Local Union No. 38, No. 81-4139
          - Burroughs v. Operating Eng'rs Local Union No. 3, No. 81-4145
          - Bloom v. International Bhd. of Teamsters, Local 468, No. 81-4151
          - Embree v. National Starch and Chem. Corp., No. 81-4159
          - Follansbee v. Davis, Skaggs & Co., No. 81-4187
          - Sausalito Pharmacy v. Blue Shield, No. 81-4198 (Box 155)
          - Potlach Corp. v. United States, No. 81-4201
          - Shipowners & Merchants Towboat Co. v. Murphy Pac. Marine Salvage Co., No. 81-4203
          - James E. Brown & Assocs. v. National Distillers & Chem. Corp., No. 81-4234
          - Smith v. Morris, No. 81-4304
          - In re Northern Dist. of Calif. Dalkon Shield IUD Prods. Liab. Litig., No. 81-4648
          - Michelson v. National Transp. Safety Bd., No. 81-7104
          - Ashcom v. Donovan, No. 81-7182
          - Tenorio v. Immigration and Naturalization Serv., No. 81-7284
        - 1983
          - Elser v. I. A. M. Nat'l Pension Fund, No. 80-6095
          - Culinary and Serv. Employees Union v. Hawaii Employee Benefit Admin., No. 81-4114; (2 folders)
          - In re Bowoon Sangsa Co., No. 81-4174; (3 folders) (Box 156)
          - Trailer Train Co. v. State Bd. of Equalization, No. 81-4188; (2 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1982
      - Eleventh circuit
        - 1983
          - United States v. O'Malley, No. 79-5083
          - In re Outrigger Club, No. 81-5057
          - Royal Typewriter Co. v. Xerographic Supplies Corp., No. 81-5311
          - United States v. Parrow, No. 81-5647 (Box 157)
          - Sly Fox Sportfishing v. Miller, No. 81-5728
          - United States v. Sorrells, No. 81-5829; (2 folders)
          - Altun Middle East Enter., Ltd. v. Southern Federated Coops., No. 81-5882
          - United States v. Hidalgo-Gato, No. 81-5993
          - United States v. Smith, No. 81-6044
          - Canino v. United States Equal Employment Opportunity Comm'n, No. 81-6162
          - First Fed. Sav. and Loan Ass'n v. Brown, No. 82-5094
          - Interstate Commerce Comm'n v. Piggy Back Shippers Ass'n, No. 82-5213; (2 folders)
          - American Druggists v. Bogart, No. 82-5352
          - Humyn v. City of Clewiston, No. 82-5402
          - Baggett v. Department of Professional Regulation, No. 82-5730
        - 1984 (Box 158)
          - United States v. Topalian, No. 81-5934
        - Miscellany, 1982, (2 folders)
      - District of Columbia circuit
        - 1984
          - Securities and Exch. Comm'n v. Ormont Drug and Chem. Co., No. 83-1814
          - Mayo v. Hodel, No. 83-1830
          - American Sec. Council v. Federal Communications Comm'n, No. 83-1840
          - Ripskis v. Department of Hous. and Urban Dev., No. 83-1921
          - Biscoe v. Arlington County, No. 83-1965
          - Martin v. Lauer, No. 83-1991; (2 folders)
          - Cross-Sound Ferry Servs. v. Interstate Commerce Comm'n, No. 83-2155
        - 1985 (Box 159)
          - Blitz v. Donovan, No. 83-2027
        - 1986
          - International Union, United Auto. Workers v. Brock, No. 83-2026; (2 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1984
  - Office File, 1955-1989 (Box 159-201)
    Correspondence, memoranda, speeches, agendas and minutes of meetings, reports, notes, background information, invitations, clippings, and printed matter.
    Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Admissions ceremonies, 1974, 1982 (Box 159)
    - Affirmative Action Program, Fourth circuit, 1979-1989, (3 folders)
    - American Judicature Society
      - 1969-1971
      - 1972-1987, (4 folders) (Box 160)
    - American Law Institute
      - 1970-1975, (3 folders)
      - 1976-1987, (7 folders) (Box 161)
    - Anniversary, Haynsworth's thirtieth on the fourth circuit court, 1987
    - Awards and honors (Box 162)
      - Clement F. Haynsworth building dedication
        - Correspondence, 1982-1983, (3 folders)
        - Clippings, 1982-1983
        - General, 1982-1983
        - Photograph and contact sheets, 1983
      - Virginia Trial Lawyers Association Distinguished Service Award, 1975
    - Bankruptcy, 1983-1989, (2 folders)
    - Biographical file, 1961-1989, undated
    - Certification, 1976-1987
    - Chief judges of the United States Court of Appeals meeting, 1970 (Box 163)
    - Chief justices conference, 1979, (2 folders)
    - Commission on Revision of the Federal Court Appellate System, 1974-1975, (3 folders)
    - Court of Military Appeals
      - 1978
      - 1979 (Box 164)
    - Federal courts symposium, Columbia, S.C., 1986, (2 folders)
    - Federal Judges Association, 1982-1989, (3 folders)
    - Federal Judicial Center
      - General
        - 1970-1974
        - 1975-1988, (3 folders) (Box 165)
      - Geographic reorganization of circuits, 1970-1981, (2 folders)
    - Fourth Economics Institute for Federal Judges, 1979, (2 folders)
    - Frank, John P.
      - 1971, 1981-1984
      - 1985-1989, (2 folders) (Box 166)
    - Frist v. Haynsworth, 1973, (2 folders)
    - General, 1971-1974
    - Institute for Court Management
      - 1983-1984, (3 folders)
      - 1985-1989, (2 folders) (Box 167)
    - Intercircuit assignments, 1981-1987
    - Interview for The Third Branch, 1980
    - Judges
      - Boreman, Herbert S., 1970-1983
      - Butzner, John D., Jr., 1967-1989, (2 folders)
      - Bryan, Albert V., 1961, 1967-1987, (3 folders)
      - Chapman, Robert F., 1983, 1987
      - Craven, James Braxton, Jr. (Box 168)
        - General, 1966-1977, (4 folders)
        - Memorial, 1977-1983, (2 folders)
      - Ervin, Sam, Jr., 1979-1989
      - Field, John A., Jr., 1971-1986 (Box 169)
      - Fourth circuit workshop, Williamsburg, Va., 1981
      - Hall, K. K., 1976-1988
      - Hemphill, Robert W., 1966-1984
      - Hoffman, Walter E., 1972-1974
      - Lewis, Oren R., 1972-1974
      - Martin, J. Robert, Jr., 1967-1974
      - Merhige, Robert R., Jr., 1969-1979
      - Murnaghan, Francis D., Jr., 1979-1989
      - Northrop, Edward S., 1974
      - Parker, John J., 1978-1989
      - Phillips, Dickson, 1978-1989 (Box 170)
      - Russell, Donald S., 1966-1987
      - Senior, 1970-1986, (2 folders)
      - Simons, Charles E., Jr., 1966-1980
      - Sneeden, Emory, 1984-1987
      - Sobeloff, Simon E.
        - 1961-1973, (2 folders)
        - 1974-1975, 1980 (Box 171)
      - Sprouse, James M., 1979-1989
      - United States Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit, 1979-1983
      - Widener, H. Emory, Jr., 1972-1989, (2 folders)
      - Wilkins, William W., Jr., 1986
      - Wilkinson, J. Harvie, III, 1984-1989
      - Winter, Harrison L.
        - 1967-1981, (2 folders)
        - 1982-1989, (3 folders) (Box 172)
    - Judgeships
      - United States Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit, additional, 1980-1983
      - United States District Courts for the Fourth Circuit, additional, 1975-1980, (2 folders)
    - Judicial
      - Compensation
        - 1974-1980, June, (2 folders)
        - 1980, July-1989, (6 folders) (Box 173)
      - Conduct standards
        - 1970-1979
        - 1980-1983, 1988, (3 folders) (Box 174)
    - Judicial Conduct and Disability Act, 1979-1980, (3 folders)
    - Judicial conferences
      - Fourth circuit
        - 1966-1967, (2 folders)
        - 1968
          - General, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 175)
          - Program
        - 1969
          - Executive session
          - General
          - Mock trial
          - Post-conference correspondence
          - Program
        - 1970 (Box 176)
          - General
          - Post-conference correspondence
          - Program
          - Special invitations
        - 1971
          - General
          - Post-conference correspondence
          - Program
          - Special invitations
        - 1972
          - General
          - Post-conference correspondence
          - Program, (2 folders) (Box 177)
          - Special invitations
        - 1973
          - General
          - Post-conference correspondence
          - Program
          - Special invitations
        - 1974
          - General, (1 folder) (Box 178)
          - Post-conference correspondence
          - Program
          - Special invitations
          - Speech
        - 1975
          - General
          - Post-conference correspondence
          - Program
          - Special invitations
        - 1976
          - General
          - Post-conference correspondence (Box 179)
          - Program
          - Special guests
          - Speech
        - 1977
          - General
          - Post-conference correspondence
          - Program
          - Special guests
          - Speech
        - 1978
          - General
          - Post-conference correspondence
          - Program
          - Special guests (Box 180)
          - Speech
        - 1979
          - General
          - Post-conference correspondence
          - Program
          - Special guests
          - Speech
        - 1980
          - General
          - Post-conference correspondence
          - Program
          - Special guests
          - Speech
        - 1981
        - 1988-1989
      - United States
        - Bicentennial Committee
          - Appropriation of funds, 1975-1977
          - General (Box 181)
            - 1975-1976, (6 folders)
            - 1976-1980, (6 folders) (Box 182)
            - 1980-1989, (4 folders) (Box 183)
          - Meetings, 1975, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 184)
        - Chief judges, meetings, 1976-1977, 1980, (3 folders)
        - Executive Committee, 1970-1974, 1979, (3 folders) (Box 185)
        - General
          - 1961-1976, (4 folders)
          - 1977-1989, (6 folders) (Box 186)
        - Meetings
          - 1969, 1974-1975, (2 folders)
          - 1976-1980, (8 folders) (Box 187)
          - 1980-1986, (4 folders) (Box 188)
    - Judicial councils
      - Fourth circuit, meetings
        - 1977-1979, (9 folders)
        - 1980, (6 folders) (Box 189)
      - United States, 1971, (1 folder) (Box 190)
    - Law clerks
      - Anderson, Joseph F., 1974-1986
      - Bentley, Arthur Lee, III, 1982-1986
      - Bondurant, Emmet J., 1960-1989
      - Byman, Martin R., 1985
      - Coenen, Dan T., 1978-1988
      - Covington, George C., 1983-1987
      - Dushman, Bernard J., 1972-1979
      - Freer, Richard, 1977-1989, undated
      - Gibbs, Coming B., Jr., 1961-1962
      - Hagan, Michael, 1975-1978
      - Iason, Larry, 1970-1974, 1984-1988
      - Ides, Allan, 1978-1989, undated
      - Johnson, Donald Peder, 1987-1988
      - Kelly, Edward J., III, 1982-1988
      - Kennedy, Joseph B., 1985-1987
      - Keyser, David R., 1976-1986
      - Kline, Scot L., 1985-1989 (Box 191)
      - Lankford, V. Thomas, Jr., 1974-1989, undated, (2 folders)
      - Lurey, Alfred S., 1966-1969
      - McIntosh, D. Laurence, 1960-1962, 1989, undated
      - McRoberts, Glenn S., 1988-1989
      - Milch, Randal S., 1984-1989
      - Mohrman, William, 1969-1981
      - Norrell, David G., 1976-1980, undated
      - Parr, Henry L., 1975-1986
      - Patrick, Pamela Morris, 1986-1989
      - Pringle, Kenneth E., 1981-1985
      - Ritchie, Larry J., 1967-1981
      - Schmider, Ernest L., 1981-1983
      - Smith, W. Mark, 1979-1989
      - Standish, Myles E., 1981-1984
      - Tennis, F. James, 1987-1989
      - Tighe, Michael W., 1963-1967
      - Tison, Claude H., Jr., 1968-1973
      - Varner, Christopher L., 1978-1988
      - Verschelden, Matthew J., 1979-1985, undated (Box 192)
      - Wasleff, John A., 1987-1988
      - Watson, Kenneth A., 1989
      - Wilkins, William W., Jr., 1969-1970
      - Wright, Henrietta, 1983-1987
    - Magistrates, 1977-1981, (4 folders)
    - Meador, Daniel John, 1978-1980, (2 folders) (Box 193)
    - Media and the law, Washington conference, 1975
    - Moot court
      - Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio, 1982
      - Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y., 1978
      - Duke University, Durham, N.C., 1978
      - University of Chicago, Chicago, Ill., 1980
      - University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, N.C., 1981
      - University of South Carolina, Columbia, S.C., 1976-1977, (2 folders)
      - University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Va., 1978-1979
    - National Conference on Appellate Justice, 1974-1976
    - National court of appeals
      - 1972
      - 1973-1981, (7 folders) (Box 194)
      - 1982-1983, 1987, undated, (3 folders) (Box 195)
    - Nomination to fourth circuit, 1955-1957, (3 folders)
    - Opinions
      - General, 1972-1980, undated
      - Printing of, 1976-1987, (3 folders) (Box 196)
      - Signed by Clement F. Haynsworth, undated, (3 folders)
    - Recommendations
      - 1957-1964
      - 1965-1981, (3 folders) (Box 197)
    - Rules
      - Federal rules
        - Appellate procedure, 1968-1989, (4 folders)
        - Civil procedure, 1976-1988 (Box 198)
        - Criminal procedure, 1972-1989, (5 folders)
      - Rule 56, prisoners' cases, 1979
      - United States Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit, 1970-1989, (2 folders) (Box 199)
    - Rules Enabling Act, 1988
    - Security, federal courthouses, 1970-1986
    - Seminar on Education and the Courts, Dillon, Colo., 1978
    - Senior status
      - 1980-1981, June, (3 folders)
      - 1981, July-Sept., undated (Box 200)
    - Thurmond, Strom, 1979-1980
    - United States Circuit Judge Nominating Commission, 1977-1979, (2 folders)
    - Walters, Johnnie McKeiver, 1970-1989
    - Ward, Bernard J., 1968-1984, (3 folders)
    - Wright, Charles Alan, 1970-1989, (10 folders) (Box 201)
- Miscellany, 1886-1989 (Box 201-205)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, speeches, writings, agendas and minutes of meetings, photographs, genealogical material, clippings, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material.
  - Furman University, Greenville, S.C. (Box 201)
    - Advisory Council
      - 1960-1963, (2 folders)
      - 1964-1973, (11 folders) (Box 202)
      - 1974-1989, (11 folders) (Box 203)
    - Alumni Association, 1962-1970
    - Baptist Convention of South Carolina, 1962-1969 (Box 204)
    - General, 1967-1984, (2 folders)
    - Haynsworth Humanities Faculty Common Room, 1982-1983
    - Pledges, 1960-1974
  - Genealogical material, undated
  - Hollins Communications Research Institute, 1975-1976
  - Photographs, 1886, 1957-1964, undated (Box 205)
  - Speech file, 1970-1980, undated, (3 folders)
  - Writings, 1974-1976, (2 folders)